Components are important right.
That is why we start with one with the app component it on the one hand is a normal angular component
but on the other hand it's also kind of special because it serves as our root component.
It's in the enlisted here in the lab module and this bootstrap array which tells angler hates a special
component.
You should bootstrap the whole application with that component being the root component.
So all our components we create will not be added to the index h team or a file are selectors will not
be added here.
Are selectors will be added to the app component.
HDMI all of fall because they exist now the well root component of our app where we add the other parts.
Enough talking about adding components lets add one.
Lets say we want to output some information about a server.
We're building a back end for our server management application and we want to output some server information.
So I will store doesn't a new folder which is a subfolder of the app folder because generally in a angler's
seal I project all your app Rollei that content will go into this app folder.
I will name it server because it will hold my server component.
And this is a good practice.
Having the folder name equal your component name and each component typically should have its own folder
though it's not a hard rule but generally it makes sense.
So here in the server folder I will add my server component.
Now a good naming convention is to have servers or the name of your component first then a dot and then
component we will later learn that there are ever building blocks in an angle or application too.
So by using filenames like this it's very easy to see what's inside the file.
And very important don't forget to add dot ts.
So for typescript because there's is what you will write this component in.
So now we get an empty file for our new component.
How do we create a component.
Now first of all a component simply is just a class that hides class so that Engler is able to instantiate
it to create objects based on the blueprint we set up here you could say.
So let's export this class so that we can use it outside of the file too.
Because as I mentioned before we're going to use our component in the app component for example to add
it there.
So we will add a class here and this class should now be named server component.
Again the naming convention here have the name of the component first server and then also the description
component.
Because later we will also learn about other parts which might then be named differently in the angular
app.
This is our class and right now it's a normal type of plus.
Nothing special about it.
We can't use it like this angler doesn't have all the information it requires.
So we should add something to it which touts angler that this is not only a normal typescript class
but instead something special component.
We do this by adding a special decorator.
Decorators are a type feature which allow you to enhance your classes for example and Hans elements
you use in your code.
It's not restricted to classes.
But here we will use a class decorator.
It's the component decorator and decorators are always attached by adding and sign in front of them.
Now this component decorator is not something types knows from the start.
So we have to import it.
We have to add in word and dis import now needs to give us access to components so we need to import
component between quali braces because from the file We're going to import this we could import our
parts too.
So we have to specifically pick the component by using this syntax and then it's from.
And now the package where we import component from is at angular core.
Now angler's ships with a couple of packages where basically groups it's functionalities and the core
package as the name implies gives us access to some of the core functionalities of angular.
So with that we import that component.
Days Africa Borland decorator is known to typescript to when it paresis this file and compiles to javascript
that is able to understand it.
Now we need to pass a javascript object Judah's component decorator to configure it because without
any configuration it's still not that valuable to angular.
But here we can set up some important information which will be stored as meta data affords class in
the background then which will tell Engler what to do with this class.
And one important information piece is the selector.
So basically the HDMI l tag by which you're able to use this component later in your average component's
templates.
We will see action soon.
The selectors should be a string.
And here you may set up any name you want but you should make sure that it is a unique selector that
you don't accidentally override a default extremal element or something like this.
So typically you prefix it with app dash and then a fitting name like server because it's a server component.
This is my own selector by which I can now later use this component in my other components.
HDMI files.
So with that set up the ever important piece we need to have is the template and here Ladd's a reference
an average external file.
I'll come back to a number.
Alternative to this soon and this external file of course needs to be created.
So in the same folder I will create a server dot component and now that HVM file.
This will hold the template the AGM all code of my component here.
So here I can now basically add any content I want.
Like for example DS server component to start simple and back to the typescript file I can now point
to this age HTML file.
We need a relative path for this.
In the end we'll all get bundled by web pick.
So we need to tell it where to find HTL file.
Well and relative to the typescript for the Pop simply s dot slash server dot component dot h him l
like this does pointing to this file with this we created our first component.
Now to use it we need to dive into app model and understand what this does because we need to change
something here to use our own component.
Let's do this in the next lecture.