In the last lecture we had a look at Stringer interpellation which is a great tool for outputting data
in a template.
Now I want to have a look at proper keybinding.
Now one important formation right away.
There are a lot of times where you can either use property binding or string interpellation.
And I will show what I mean in a second.
Let's go to our service component where we manage all the servers and I want to allow the user to add
new service at least soon.
I want to allow that.
So we don't need a button where I say ad server on it.
And I would just add some US as classis button and Button primary to make this part look nice.
This is all using normal bootstraps as classes though nothing to do with angular and to reflect this
change in my service component here.
I also want to comment out the inline template and point to the external template again.
So template or else should point to my server component toward aged him or fall like this.
Now with this if I saved as we see that button here right now it doesn't make any sense that I'm able
to click this button because it doesn't do anything we haven't learned to react to a button click yet.
So I will add a new property in my typescript code here which will name allow news server and set it
to false.
So now this is all a number property holding a boolean value.
So true or false in this case false because I don't want to allow the user to create a new server and
you could again imagine that these are somehow deprived dynamically.
We will soon work with some dynamic data so any HMO file here I now want to disable the button.
And as you probably know there is a disabled attribute you can add like days we now save as the buttons
disabled I can click it.
That's nice but that's hard coded into HVM L.
Now maybe this allows news server code here changes.
However maybe it's not said to does all the time.
So then we wouldn't be able to react to this.
And I can actually demonstrate this by for now in the constructor which is simply a method executed
at the point of time this component is created by angler by their calling set timeout.
A normal javascript function.
And here I define after which period of time or after how many milliseconds something should happen.
So after 2000 milliseconds which are two seconds I want to execute a function.
And here I'm using as 6 arrow function.
This syntax might look strange.
It's almost the same as function like this with some difference when it comes to handling this key word.
But in the end here you passed the arguments and here you have the function body more importantly in
your.
I can set allow news server and no this would not work in the average syntax because this would then
be referring to something else can set it to true.
So after two seconds does we'll be switch to True and since we hardcoded this of course to the fact
our button here at all it stays disabled.
So I want to bind it to allow news server so now to make this disabled functionality dynamic we can
blind to it by enclosing it in square brackets square brackets indicate to angular that we're using
property binding that we want to dynamically bind some property and disabled the HMO attribute in the
end.
In normal HVM all only sets a specific property on the underlying Dom element.
You might note that each HVM l element you use is parsed by the browser and kind of translated into
an element on the document object model.
This is totally unrelated to angular.
And therefore we have an element in this form and this element has a couple of properties.
A lot of these can't even be set frou attributes on th shemale element.
Well one of the properties is to disable property and you can set the disabled attribute.
But here we're not using to disable attribute anymore with the square brackets we are directly binding
Tudor's native disabled property.
This HDMI element has.
So now we can set this equal to.
And now with windy quotation marks here an expression which for this property resolves to a boolean.
But for our properties and number Taieb might be required because again you can bind to a lot of properties
basically to all the h l element properties.
We'll soon learn that there are also Amur properties you can buy into.
So for now I can simply pass allow news server here.
My property name because this will resolve to True or false.
Exactly devalue the same the property needs because it has to decide whether it should be disabled or
not.
So now with that if we reverse this.
So by adding an exclamation mark we made sure that this is only disabled if this is for.
So if we allow a new server it's not true.
Otherwise you would do exactly the opposite.
So now with the exclamation mark if we go back to the APAC it's disabled.
But after two seconds let me reload this.
It becomes enabled because now we're binding to this disabled property this native element property
we're binding us to our own typescript property here and to convene the thing is and this is what angler's
all about that this will update dynamically.
So once allow news server changes is a change in the dorms since the button gets enabled.
One of the main reasons why you use angular.
It makes it very easy for you to interact with your dorm to change something stare at runtime like we
do here.
That is property binding in.
Now as I mentioned besides binding to HVM element properties like we do here you can also mine to our
properties for example of directives something we haven't learned about yet.
And your own components something I will also show you later.
So does this property binding.
Before moving on the other two forms of data binding.
Let's find out where you could actually use string interpellation instead of property binding.