In the last lectures we learn a lot including the creation of a new component by hand.
Now there also is an alternative to creating it manually when using the Seelye you can open a new terminal
window or command line Leave the end user window running.
That's important don't close it.
And in this new window we can use some steel I command to also create a new component.
Let's say we want to have our single server components here in a number of components are nested into
a number of component servers multiple servers component.
We can create this manually by adding a service folder with our component or we use to see light with
energy and there we have a generate command which allows us to generate some elements some elements
supported by angler.
One such element is a component so we can create a new component with energy generated component and
then passing the name service like this.
You can also use a shortcut and instead of energy generated component you could say Engy G C which does
the same.
So if you hit enter what this will do is it will give you a new folder in your app folder with the name
of your component servers.
And then there you basically find the same files as you had for the app component aged LCS as TS enters
Spack file which basically is used for testing.
Now I will remove this.
We will later have a section about testing and we'll have a look at restyling later too.
For now let's say it is in this service component that we want to output our single server.
Well we already have this decorator selector app server.
So in this template of the service component we can override the default text with app server and maybe
simply replicate this so that we have two components because remember components are reusable.
We can use the same component as often as we want by simply using it selector as often as we want.
So now we have two service here and with this in our service component you need to make sure that you
always update the app module.
Now do you see I should do this automatically which is why you already find the import and declaration
in this file.
But make sure you really do have it here.
With this we can go to our service component types and fault to check the selector which is app dash
service and then we can go to our app team of our app component HMO file and update deselected to use
this new component instead of the old one.
With this if we now save this and go back to our application it looks almost the same as before we see
our a single server component twice.
But if we inspect the code here in the developer tools of chrome for example you'll see that we have
this our app servers component to this newly created component.
And in between we have two single AB server components.
So with that we learned a couple of important things about how to create components manually or with
to Selye how we can nest them into each other that we can use components selectors in any Obert template
of any other component and how we can replicate components by simply using them.
Well multiple times using their selectors multiple times.
Let's dive into how we can actually style them what you can do regarding the style and the template
of components.