In the last lecture we had a look at event binding.
Number four focusing on two way binding and explaining what this is.
There's one other important thing you need to know about even binding.
Let's say before disburden button we also have a label server name.
And then more importantly we have the input which we maybe give bootstrap class of form control here
and want to allow the user to enter the name of the server which should get created.
So here we could listen to the input event.
This is a normal dorm event provide the input element which is fire and the user types.
And we could execute on update server name because it will be fired on every keystroke.
So let's add this method to our component here and now I somehow want to output what the user entered.
Right now what the value of this field is that we can do this by passing dollar sign event here and
Thaller assign events super important is kind of our reserved variable name.
You can use the template when using event binding for this event so only between these quotation marks
your dollar sign event will simply be the data emitted with that event.
So input and click are default events provided by the dorm you could say.
And they ship some data when they are fired the click event gives us an object which for example holds
the coordinates where we clicked and the event also gives us some data or some information about the
event that we can capture this data with Dollar Sign event passed as an argument to the method we're
calling or used anywhere between these quotation marks in their Kolgrim executing dollar sign event
something to keep in mind reserve the word which gives us access to event data.
So now we pass this to an update server name.
So here we know we will receive this event and this will be of type any for now.
So now let's simply log it to the console so that we can see it in this debug log.
If we do this and I now type something here watched a console on the right a couple of outputs were
there four to be precise because I typed four characters did four keystrokes.
So the input band was fired four times.
And if you have a look at this event we get a couple of information here.
For example the target and the target simply is the HDMI element on which this event occurred.
So here on the target since the input element of we scroll down we also got the value test and this
is what the user entered.
So what we can do now in our typescript code is we can set a server name property which is an empty
string by default.
And then here in our update server name instead of logging it we could say this server name and we just
learned that on the event which is a type event as we know also saw here we have a target and on the
target we have a value and it is only available because the target is of type input element.
So this is why my ID doesn't like it.
We can explicitly inform it about the type in typescript by adding HDMI input element here.
In front of it like this.
And again this is just needed to inform typescript that we know that the type of the HDMI element of
this event will be an HMO input element.
We do this explicit casting with this text with the opening and closing tag of the smaller and greater
than sign and to type in between.
So with that we assign this value to our server name where we can now do is in the AGM of file here
we can output this for now.
So a strict interpellation we could output the server name Melodia input.
If we save this and go back to this application and I type test server here you see this dynamically
updates melodeon port.
This is how you can use this dollar sign event object to fetch the event data.
Now with that let's move on to two way data binding to kind of finished as little example eppi it for
now.