Now are you already a component ninja.
We learned a lot about components about the templates options we have there and about the styles I want
and focus on the last property we see in this component decorator for now.
The selector I already mentioned that this has to be a unique selector so that you don't override accidentally
an already existing element or maybe a component made available by a number of third party package you
use in your project.
There's one other piece of information about the selector.
Though you don't have to use this type of selector right now our selector is the same selector as we
use it in C..
As for selecting element so we have app server this year as the element and this is recognized by angular
because the selector we chose is app servers and this basically just looks how you use select elements
in C S S right.
We select the age tree element by just typing Atri here.
We select the app service element by just typing app service here.
So that actually works Legacy's as selector and therefore you are not limited to selecting by element.
You could put this into square brackets to use the attribute selector.
So in Zia's as you can select elements by attribute by enclosing that attribute in square brackets.
And now if you save this you would see that our app actually is broken because if we have a look at
the error message app servers it's an unknown element because now our code angler doesn't recognize
app service anymore because we changed the selector to be an attribute.
So to make this work again we would have to comment this out or remove it and maybe add a div or any
other element a normal aged human element which has the app servers attribute now.
Now with days custom attribute added now.
Now the Eberts again because now angler's selects the element by attribute and not by the element itself
because we changed the selector and Navier alternative is to select by and I'm just going to comment
this out so that the code is still there for reference to select by class.
So with a dot at the beginning app servers again just like in C S S.
So here we can now select by class.
So let's add a new day of the year which has a class of app servers which we of course could now also
style.
But besides that it's also recognized by Engler as a selector which is why we still see the app.
Now these are all options you have.
As a side note selecting by ID won't work that's not supported by angular and all those pseudo selectors
like hover and so on also don't work and you typically use the elements style here.
App servers for components.
We will soon learn about directives.
Another feature where this is different.
But for components you typically create your own elements and therefore you don't use that style and
you don't use the attribute style.
Instead you use app Cirus like element but it is important to understand that you are not limited to
this.
And there might be use cases where you want to use a different selector