In the last lecture we had a close look at what happens at the point of time we wisit localhost 4200
here in the browser.
We understood that the index HVM file is served that it will contain a bunch of scripts here which can
execute executed which then basically start the angular app dangler app gets the important information
deaded should know the app component that it should analyze it with that information the angular code
is able to parse this year does AB root component here.
Understand that and insert our anger application at this point and that is why we don't see loading
dot dot dot which would still be in the source code of this page as you can see.
But instead why we see this because angular overrides this at runtime because they as well what it does
for what is SCHABAS.
So now that we had a close look at this startup process let's have a closer look at these Cobbold and
or add components and general components are a key feature in angular.
You build your whole application by composing it from a couple of components which you create on your
own.
Now we do start with this app component the root component you should say which holds our and how our
entire application basically in the end.
So this route component this app component will be the component where we later nest or add our other
components too.
So to this template does HVM file off.
Yep component.
This is where we will later add our other components.
Typically we might have a web page like this with a header with home and users then a main area and
a side bar maybe.
Now if we have a look this would be a fitting component to header and maybe also the items on the hair
could be their own Kebon could be you don't have to.
You will learn from the Course how I approach the splitting up of an application into separate components.
We also have of course our main area the bar here as components and that is the core idea behind Engler
built components.
Each component has its own template its own age all killed maybe its own styling.
And more importantly also its own business logic and business to great benefit.
It allows us to split up your complex application your complex web page into reusable parts.
You may use a component more than once and that allows you to easily replicate that business logic.
Replicate that styling or in general make a finely controlled piece in your application without having
to crunch everything into one single script file one single file instead.
It's very easy to update very easy to exchange and again re-usable.
So let's have a closer look at how we actually create a component and what does that component thing
does in the next lecture.