In last lectures we learn a lot about how we can use property binding and stringin jubilation to output
data in the template.
Let's now react to events.
For example we have a pattern here.
And after two seconds this badness enabled so would be nice we could do something once we clicked the
button.
Now I will soon show you how we can actually add a news server how we can add a new replication of our
server a selector of our server component to year.
For now what I want to do is I want to output something.
I will remove this text here and instead here I want to output the value of a property or create this
property.
And again you make more energy on it for now I will come back to this.
I will name it Server creation status and initially able to set it to no server was created like this.
Now this property can be output wires string a tribulation server creation status.
And I just told you I don't want to continue outputting data.
We want to listen to events.
So I promised it we'll do it.
I will add another method below here and I will name this method on create server d on at the beginning
to kind of make clear that this will be triggered from within my template.
You don't have to name it on something but it kind of makes it easier to understand who will call this
method.
Well the user will basically by doing something some event will call it that is what I want to symbolize
with that.
So if you're able to set the server creation status to server was created.
So the missing piece of course is to call this method.
And now here is where if when binding comes into play we want to listen to this click event here.
And typically you have the on click attribute on the HDMI element where you can now execute some Chalis
dropped code.
We won't use that with angler though.
Here we have the Sendak's angler offers us event binding which uses parentheses like property binding
used square brackets for events.
Parentheses are a signal that we're using when binding.
And here we have to specify the name of DBAN between the parentheses.
For example click and you can basically bind to all the events made available by the HDMI attribute.
You're placing us on.
So if you have on click on mouse enter you could bind to click mouse enter without the on at the beginning.
So we are blind to the click event.
And now between the quotation marks we put the code we want to execute.
Once this event occurs not oftentimes you will call a method here.
So let's do it as LEDs point to the method we want to execute which is on create server with parentheses.
So this method will now get executed whenever we click the button.
As a side note you don't have to execute a method here.
You could also put the code you want to execute right between quotation marks.
Oftentimes this is not very good because you want to execute more code if some event happens.
But if all you want to do is set some boolean property to True for example well.
You can definitely do inline the template as a general rule though you shouldn't put too much logic
into your templates though.
So now we're binding to click event and we execute on create server method when it occurs.
So let's see there's an action in our application.
Let's reload the page.
The button gets enabled and now watch this part here.
So I click the button it changes the server was created because we are triggering our own methods here.
And this is how a simple event binding works.
Use parentheses.
Event name in between and then between the quotation marks the code you want to execute.
When this event occurs