Sell days is the page as we see it right now in the project we created at the end of the last section
of empty page year in order to complete guide we reach it at local host 4200 days is where our development
server hosted by the Selye or spun up by TACL I will host our angular application.
Now the content we see here can be changed by going to the app component HVM of file in our app folder
and then here we can output some text lets say in the app component here in the age free tag and normal
HVM Altec.
Therefore if we save this we will see it here and it automatically has to bootstrap textile and so on
because we added bootstrap at the end of the last section too.
But yes it might seem kind of obvious that we see it here it is also kind of strange.
How does our browser or how does a server hosting our app know that it should render the content of
app component HVM all here.
You could argue it's the only component we have right now and we will take a closer look at component's
soon.
But that is not the reason.
And actually this is not the file served by the server.
Instead the index HDMI file here is served by the server and remembered that I told you that angular
is a framework which allows you to create single page application.
This is the single page which has served the index HDMI file.
Now if you have a look at this file we see this is a normal HTL file.
We defined a title we could see on the tab in the browser year.
And the body of this file is very interesting.
Here we get this app rude thing with a loading dot dot dot in between.
Now clearly we don't see it loading dot dot dot here.
So somehow this index HVM Ulfar seems to have changed and it did app Rootie year of course is not a
default age HTML element.
Instead as is one of our own components we will soon dive into how we create our own components but
the Seelye created one for us.
The root component of our application to component which will tie together our whole application in
the end and all the files in the app folder here which have component in their name.
So these files are related to this component.
I will go into more detail about these files and one of the next lectures for now let's take a closer
look at the app component thought t as followed a typescript file here.
Here you can see that we have to at component decorator does seems to be important but more importantly
right now you'll see that there we have this select or property which assigns a string as a value and
does string hold.
App root not as clearly as the same text as in our index HDMI file.
And this actually is the information angular needed to be able to replace this part here in this index
H-2A I'll file with the template off this component the component having this selector and the template
on this component simply is the content here in this app component h file.
Now whilst I will dive deeper into how to create components and how to configure them this is what basically
happens at the startup though.
The missing information is how is angular triggered.
How is it kicked off to actually run over our body here of these index HVM file.
And the answer is in the final index age of the file getting served in the browser and we can verify
this by inspecting the source code here we got a couple of script imports at the end.
These are injected by the seal automatically.
So that is why we don't see it here in the raw index.
HD mouthfull here we don't have any script imports but whenever does N-G serve Burroughs's rebuilds
our project it will create bundles.
Javascript script bundles and automatically add derived imports in the index H.T. mouthfull a little
convenience functionality for us.
So in the final file DS script imports here are present and DS script imports will contain our own code
to sell these script files are there for executed and they're actually the first code to be executed.
And that is just something you have to keep in mind is to code we write in our main dot TS file.
That is why it's called Main.
This is the first code which gets executed.
Let's have a closer look at it then.
Here you see that we get a couple of imports then we check if we are in production mode or not.
You basically turn off some warning messages I can tell you that.
But most importantly here this line is now bootstraps starts our angular application by passing app
module tutors Methot and AB Marchal refers to this file here.
Now if we have a look at this file here we actually see dad somehow we kind of like to Component have
to strange at thing here.
I will dive into this in a couple of lectures too.
But most important for now here we get this bootstrap array which basically lists all the components
which should been known to Engler at the point of time it analyzes our index aged him l file and here
the circle closes.
Because here we reference our app component.
So angular gets started this made or TS file gets started there.
We bootstrap an angler application and we pass this module as an argument in this module we tell angular
hey there is this app component which you know when you try to start yourself and angular.
Now analyze this tiap component reads the set up we pass year and therefore is selector EBP route.
And now Eyler is able to handle AB root in the index HDMI file and it knows.
All right does is the selector I know you told me that I should know it because it was listed in this
bootstrap array in the module this component.
So now I know that here I should insert the app component and the app component happens to have some
HDL code a template attached to it which is this a treat tag and desires howdie Engler application starts.
This is why we see what we see.
Now that was a load of information regarding the app startup but it's key to understand how does starts
with this information we can now proceed and dive deeper into how components actually work what they
are how we can create our own ones and what this app module here does in detail.
So let's move on.