We understood that templates are important and that we can either use them in line here or point to
an external file.
What about styles.
We also have this style or else property here and we have DS C S S files.
What can we do with those.
Let's go back to our app component for this.
Here we got a tree tag and a horizontal line.
And if we have a look at our application it's not that pretty right.
The I'm in the app component text here are all the text actually is sitting right on the you're not
super pretty.
Now since we use bootstrap Of course we can use some bootstrap classes to enhance this so we could add
a day of with our container class around it then add a row.
And this is just using D.C.'s as framework bootstrap.
So these are some siestas classes provided by this framework nothing angler's specific.
And then we could add a column of your excess wealth to have one column on all device whiffs.
Now if we add this we added some styling some normalcy as a styling nothing angler's specific.
And our app looks a little bit nicer now.
This is great but we can also use some tools given to us by angularity.
Let's say does I'm India component heading here.
We want to change that style.
Maybe we want to give some blue color.
We can do it just by going to the app component C S S file which defines the styling for does component.
And now we can use or write normal SEUS us code.
So override the style of D.H. free tag and set its color to some Baloo.
So maybe Tudor's dark blue here.
If we now save this and we have a look at our application you see it's dark blue.
Now this is how you can use this style file this C-s as file referenced in the app component here too
to find the styles for a component.
Now just like we were able to choose between external file and inline code for the template we can do
the same for the styling.
You know does that style you or else is an array year whereas template you were a Wasn't it is this.
Because we could reference multiple external style sheets here so you could add pointers to stylesheets.
But besides that I'm going to comment this out.
You can also set up a number property which is just styles.
This also takes an array but now it takes an array of strings where you define the style in this string.
So now in this file here I'm going to use back ticks again to be able to write a multi-line expression
here and then we could set up a tree here.
And to really show you that this is different I will set the color cube.
Now let's not say dark blue but you Dodger blue.
And if I now save this and we go back to the application you see the blue updated because now the inline
style is taking over.
I commented out the other one just like with the template you have to decide which one to use.
You can't combine style or else and styles but both important here has to be an array that's different
to template.
You must only have one template you may have multiple style files or style definitions and you can choose
between inline and extra in a file.
The rules are basically the same as for template.
If you have more code in there using an external file is a good idea if it's a short style definition
like this.
Why don't you just put it into the typescript file.
This is how you can work with templates and styles